<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>matt morris</title><link>https://mattmorris.ca/</link><description>Recent content on matt morris</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://mattmorris.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>about</title><link>https://mattmorris.ca/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mattmorris.ca/about/</guid><description>Composer and pianist Matt Morris began writing music immediately after starting piano lessons. Classical training led to an interest in jazz and other modern styles which took him through the MacEwan jazz program. He holds Music Diplomas in jazz piano performance and composition as well as a Bachelors of Music degree majoring in composition.
Since university Matt has been actively performing, composing, accompanying and teaching.
Email: mattmorris@mattmorris.ca</description></item><item><title>contact</title><link>https://mattmorris.ca/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mattmorris.ca/contact/</guid><description>mattmorris@mattmorris.ca</description></item><item><title>Dunst Volume Indicator for Pipewire</title><link>https://mattmorris.ca/projects/dunst-volume-indicator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mattmorris.ca/projects/dunst-volume-indicator/</guid><description>Date: August 18, 2022
Here I will be creating a clever volume indicator for linux systems without a dedicated desktop environment. The end result is to look nice: Full script can be found on my GitHub.
It must serve the following:
work with Pipewire work with Dunst allow for incremental increases in volume called from keybinding such as sxhkd round appropriately to save my ocd from seeing numbers like 37% mute if volume reaches 0% Basic setup</description></item><item><title>endeavours</title><link>https://mattmorris.ca/endeavours/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mattmorris.ca/endeavours/</guid><description>Music With Mandy Composer, pianist Colour Me Sad Composer, pianist The Magic That is Me the first musical by Colour Me Sad. It explores many emotions including love, excitement, anxiety and calm. The musical follows a dream sequence experienced by Max, a young girl who splits her time between her mom’s house and her dad’s house. She loses all the colour in her rainbow bedroom and goes on an adventure through a dreamland to retrieve the lost colours.</description></item><item><title>Install Seafile on a Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://mattmorris.ca/projects/seafile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mattmorris.ca/projects/seafile/</guid><description>Updated on August 27, 2022 for Seafile Server 9.0.2 on Raspberry Pi Bullseye.
Seafile is a free and open source file syncing tool that can be self-hosted on a raspberry pi. Below is a brief comparison of similar programs that are also free and self-hostable on a pi:
Program Share files with others Apps Speed Seafile yes anything fast Nextcloud yes anything slow Syncthing no poor iOS support fast We&amp;rsquo;ll be installing Seafile on a raspberry pi 4 and setting up a reverse proxy so we can connect to it remotely though our own domain.</description></item><item><title>Jellyfin, Sonarr, Radarr and Deluge On Raspberry Pi 4</title><link>https://mattmorris.ca/projects/jellyfin_on_raspberrypi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mattmorris.ca/projects/jellyfin_on_raspberrypi/</guid><description>Install Jellyfin, Sonarr, Radarr and Deluge On a Raspberry Pi 4 Updated on August 27, 2022. Read here for the basics of getting a Raspberry Pi setup for server use.
Install docker and docker-compose Install docker.
curl -sSL https://get.docker.com | sh Add docker to the usergroup pi.
sudo usermod -aG docker pi Preferred way to install docker-compose (from here).
NOTE: You can run these commands in one shot by pressing Ctrl-x-e (that&amp;rsquo;s control x and keep holding control while pressing e) and pasting the lines as is.</description></item><item><title>music</title><link>https://mattmorris.ca/music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mattmorris.ca/music/</guid><description>Music With Mandy Composer, pianist Colour Me Sad Composer, pianist The Magic That is Me the first musical by Colour Me Sad. It explores many emotions including love, excitement, anxiety and calm. The musical follows a dream sequence experienced by Max, a young girl who splits her time between her mom’s house and her dad’s house. She loses all the colour in her rainbow bedroom and goes on an adventure through a dreamland to retrieve the lost colours.</description></item><item><title>music</title><link>https://mattmorris.ca/posts/music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mattmorris.ca/posts/music/</guid><description>Music With Mandy Composer, pianist Colour Me Sad Composer, pianist The Magic That is Me the first musical by Colour Me Sad. It explores many emotions including love, excitement, anxiety and calm. The musical follows a dream sequence experienced by Max, a young girl who splits her time between her mom’s house and her dad’s house. She loses all the colour in her rainbow bedroom and goes on an adventure through a dreamland to retrieve the lost colours.</description></item><item><title>other</title><link>https://mattmorris.ca/other/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mattmorris.ca/other/</guid><description>Dunst Volume Indicator for Pipewire
Install Seafile on a Raspberry Pi
Jellyfin, Sonarr, Radarr and Deluge On Raspberry Pi 4
Setup Your Raspberry Pi</description></item><item><title>Setup Your Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://mattmorris.ca/projects/setup_pi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mattmorris.ca/projects/setup_pi/</guid><description>Installing the OS to an SD Card Install the Raspberry Pi Imager. Under CHOOSE OS select Raspberry Pi OS (Other) and Raspberry Pi OS Lite (64-bit). Click the settings cog to setup wifi, enable ssh, change the default password and change locale settings. Under CHOOSE STORAGE select your inserted sd card.
Find your pi&amp;rsquo;s ip address Raspberry Pi Documentation - Remote Access Boot up the pi and find your new ip address.</description></item></channel></rss>